-不是我的总统  -不是我的总统
- Not my president! - Not my president!
不要安德伍德
废除总统选举团
-不是我的总统  -不是我的总统
- Not my president! - Not my president!
人民很愤怒
The people are angry.
九周前  我们国家举行了一场大选
Nine weeks ago, we had an election in this country,
但是由于两个州拒绝认证选举结果
but because two states refused to certify,
康威和我都没拿到270张选举人票
neither Conway nor myself received the 270 electoral votes
而这是胜选的必要条件
required for victory.
所以他们每天早上聚集在这里
So they gather here every morning
来履行他们神圣的权利
to exercise their magnificent right,
被第一修正案保障的权利
guaranteed by the First Amendment...
发出他们愤怒的声音
to let their angry voices be heard.
就这样  感恩节  圣诞节
And so, Thanksgiving, Christmas,
再加上半个一月来了又去
and half of January have come and gone,
政府的三大分支全都深陷危机
and all three branches of government are in crisis.
国会吵成一团
The Congress is in disarray,
最高法院少了一位法官  必将陷入僵局
the Supreme Court is down a justice and doomed to deadlock,
而行政机关也群龙无首
and the executive branch is without a boss.
你看  我觉得
You see, my feeling is,
国父们就是乏了
I think the Founding Fathers, they just got tired.
说真的  谁能怪他们呢
And really, can you blame them?
你怎么可能把方方面面都考虑周全
I mean, you can't think of everything.
各种意外  各种难以避免的灾难
Black swans, Murphy's Law.
到了一定程度
I mean, at a certain point,
你也只能放弃  交叉手指
you just have to sign off and cross your goddamn fingers
祈求能有个好结果
and hope for the best.
或者使用"扔硬币原理"
Or adopt "flipism,"
这是一种伪哲学  意思是
a pseudo-philosophy of life in which
生活中最重要的事都要通过扔硬币来决定
the most important decisions are made by the flipping of a coin.
这个说法最先出现在迪士尼的漫画书
It was first introduced in the Disney comic book
《硬币决定法》里  我最喜欢这期了
Flip Decision, one of my favorites,
里面讲到巴蒂教授说服唐老鸭
in which Donald Duck is persuaded by Professor Batty
所有重大的人生决定
to make all the most important decisions
都通过扔硬币来决断
based on the flipping of a coin.
"生活就是场赌博
"Life is but a gamble.
让扔硬币原理指引你"
Let flipism guide your ramble."
我们以前也有过这种麻烦
We've had this sort of trouble before.
1800年大选  杰斐逊对伯尔
The election of 1800, Jefferson versus Burr.
他们最后打成了平手  每人73张选举人票
They wound up in a tie. 73 electoral votes each.
那是当时的胜选票数
That was the number required then,
这时国会试图解决这种
and that's when Congress tried to address
国父们根本想象不到的局面
what the Founding Fathers just couldn't imagine.
于是  第十二修正案诞生了
And, poof, the Twelfth Amendment was born.
里面说  如果各州不能认证选举结果
And it says that if the states don't certify,
那么就由众议院来挑选总统
it's the House that chooses the president
由参议院来选副总统
and the Senate that chooses the vice president.
众议院有点乱  说不清楚
Now the House is a bit of a mess,
但是参议院选副总统的办法可是挺民主的
but the Senate is rather democratic in how they choose the VP.
一人一票
One person, one vote.
但如果还是平局
But if there's a tie...
就该唐老鸭登场了
and this is where Donald Duck comes in,
选举的结果
it's resolved...
全看这硬币一扔
by the toss of a coin.
这办法简洁得见了鬼
A solution that's elegant as hell.
不过现代政治哪有什么简洁可言
But then there's no elegance in modern politics.
只剩下见鬼了
It's mostly hell.
美国总统的宝座花落谁家
The identity of the next President of these United States
决定权再次落到了这一帮
is once again in the hands of a bunch of
自私自利  嗜财如命
self-serving, money-hungry,
阿谀谄媚  贪恋权势的政治家手里
boot-licking, power-seeking politicians
而加以利诱  或者迎头痛击
who can be seduced or sucker punched
或者要挟就能让他们服从
or blackmailed into submission.
我只需要比另一个人多一票就行
And all I need is just one more vote than the other guy.
如你所见  国父们根本没想到会有这种局面
As you can see, the Founding Fathers didn't plan for this.
而我想到了
But I did.
我就是你的新爹
Meet your new daddy.
人人影视倾情奉献
翻译   草草
翻译   国士章鱼X
翻译   杏仁斯嘉丽
翻译   煮粥
翻译   吃冰棒
翻译   肉松
时间轴   壬虚浪影
时间轴   念念
时间轴   西·查
后期   饿得慌
顾问   老杜
校对   草草
总监   草草
纸牌屋
第五季  第五集
好
Right.
你能感觉到  对吧  简直身临其境
You can feel it, right? It's like you're there.
是不是跟真的一样
Doesn't that look just like it?
在我看来简直就是那个地方
To me, it is that place.
你还好吧
You okay, man?
好  当然好了
Yeah. Of course.
真的有帮助  很管用的
It really helps. Very effective.
是啊  我很乐意帮你拉更多投资来
Yeah. I'd be happy to help you find more funding for it.
如果你情绪有点激动的话
If you're feeling a little worked up...
什么
What?
情绪激动
Little worked up?
两个多月以前我就当选成为美国总统了
I was elected President of the United States over two months ago.
但不知为何  现在国会将决定选举结果
But somehow, Congress is now deciding the election.
所以原谅我有些
So forgive me for being a little...
-威尔  -情绪激动
- Will... - ...worked up.
东尼应该不是话中有话
I don't think Tony was implying anything.
当然  那好
Of course. Good.
我去准备一下
I'm gonna get myself ready.
我可不想这副样子去参加活动
I don't want to go to the event looking like this.
是啊
Right.
谢谢  东尼
Thanks, Tony.
罗梅洛的幕僚长坚称他不在这儿
Romero's chief of staff insists he's not in town.
-你相信她吗  -不
- And do you believe her? - No.
但她在特区待得比他久
But she's been in D.C. longer than he has.
她总会顾及自己的
At some point she'll take care of herself.
你告没告诉她  我不想跟他谈
Well, did you tell her I have no interest in discussing
宣战委员会的事
the Declaration of War Committee with him?
我表明了
I expressed our desire
我们想跟议员进行一次客气而有成效的谈话
for a civil and productive meeting with the Congressman.
找到他
Well, find him.
要是他想躲着我
If he wants to hide from me,
那就当着我的面做
he can do it to my face.
是  先生
Yes, sir.
还有  道格
And, Doug.
今天外面有多少抗议者
How many protestors are out there today?
比昨天多
More than yesterday.
但他们已经尽力
But they're doing their best
让他们远离白宫了
to divert them away from the White House.
我不知道哪样更糟
I don't know what's worse...
是他们抗议喊口号的声音
the sound of their chanting
还是他们不喊时的寂静
or the sound of silence when they're not.
我去工作了  先生
I'll get to work, sir.
早上好  奥古斯都
Good morning, Augustus.
艾瑞克  我...
Well, Eric, I...
抱歉  他们让我坐着  但
I'm sorry. They told me to sit, but, uh--
没事  完全没关系  我
No, no, no. It's perfectly fine. I...
我想不到还有谁
I can't imagine anyone else who would...
会比你更喜欢这个
well, enjoy this more than you.
我们在斯波特瑟尔韦尼亚相遇后
You know, I only started it
我才开始做的这个
after you and I met in Spotsylvania.
你对细节的注重简直是
The attention to detail is... It's just...
没错
It is, yes.
我有
I've got...
我
I mean, I...
抱歉  我现在有点不知所错
I'm sorry, I'm a... a little overwhelmed by the moment.
就是
It's just...
我有一种感觉  就好像
I have this feeling, as if, uh...
我曾经想象过这个场景
I've imagined this somehow.
我知道这听起来
I know that sounds, uh...
你连他背包上的扣子都做出来了
You've even got the button on his haversack.
是啊
Yes.
我觉得人们会低估
I think people underestimate...
注重细节
the importance of detail...
对整体感觉的影响
to the overall impact.
是啊
Yeah.
血腥角专家肯定会非常钦佩的
The Bloody Angle experts would be very impressed.
我们在斯波特瑟尔韦尼亚相遇时  你怎么知道
When we met in Spotsylvania, how did you know...
那么多关于奥古斯都的细节
so many specific things about Augustus, uh...
关于奥古斯都·安德伍德之死
about Augustus Underwood's death?
知道他牺牲的确切地点
I mean, the very spot where he died?
知道他的脑袋被石头砸扁了
The... the fact that his skull had been crushed with a rock?
知道他们把他葬在无名冢里
That they buried him in an unmarked grave? I mean...
这么多细节
the detail of all that.
希望你能原谅我
Hope you'll forgive me, uh...
原谅什么
For?
我那天见到了副总统弗兰西斯·安德伍德
I was meeting Vice President Francis Underwood.
我觉得应该给他讲个精彩的传说
I... thought he deserved a good story.
慢着  等等
Wait, wait a minute. You...
-那些全是你编的  -那个
- you made all that up? - Well...
我自由发挥了一下
I took some liberties.
但  我也说不好  我一开了头
But, well, I don't know, once it started,
就能清晰地看见了
it came to me so clearly...
-艾瑞克  对吗  -对  先生
- It's Eric, yeah? - Yes, sir.
抗议人群吗
The crowd?
对  抱歉  你刚才要说什么
Yes. I'm sorry, what were you about to say?
我无意唐突  先生
I don't mean to overstep, sir...
但外面的人
but the people out there...
我不在乎他们说什么
I don't care what they're saying.
在我看来  人的命运
And the way I see it, a person's destiny is, you know...
是注定的
sealed.
国会将于四天后选定总统
我们踏入了未知领域
We are in uncharted territory here.
好  但是唐尼  帮个忙好吗
All right. But, Donny, do me a favor, okay?
-让宪法  -我能说完吗
- Let the Constitution-- - Can I finish?
等等  让宪法行使它的职责
Hold on. Just let the Constitution do its job.
好吧  乔  让我说完一次
Okay, Joe, Joe, I'm gonna finish for once.
现在有选民提起个诉
You've got voters filing individual suits...
-对  -田纳西和俄亥俄都有
- Right. - ...in Tennessee and Ohio,
都堆在最高法院了
and they are jammed up in the Supreme Court.
就像别的一切
Like everything else,
这个国家的日常事务被中断了
the day-to-day workings of this country are on hold.
好  或许是被中断了  但你猜怎么
Okay, they may be on hold, but guess what?
据我所知
Last time I checked,
大家仍然在领社保支票
everybody was still getting their Social Security checks.
没错  但如果达到债务上限了呢
Yeah, but if the debt limit is reached?
拜托  让我说完
Come on. Let me finish now.
再说一遍  这就是为什么我们有宪法
Again, it's why we have a Constitution.
我知道看上去很混乱
I know it looks messy.
民主就很混乱  但你猜怎么
Democracy's messy. But guess what?
这种乱局是有规律的
There is a method to that madness.
我说不好  乔
I don't know, Joe.
如今是混乱胜过规律
It's more madness than method right now.
如果政府停摆
I mean, if the government does shut down,
那些社保支票或许就要停发
those Social Security checks, they might not go out.
如果政府停摆
If the government shuts down,
谁知道国会还能不能选出总统
who knows if Congress can even pick a president?
众议院的每个州只有一票
Each state in the House just gets one vote.
那么如果特拉华州和罗德岛州这样的小州
So if smaller states like Delaware and Rhode Island
不能达成共识
can't reach a consensus...
-嗯  -不  是这样的
- Right. - No, it's true.
如果一两个
I mean, if one or two of these
非常固执的国会成员
really stubborn members of Congress
决定顽固抵抗  可能要耗数月
decides they're going to hold this up, it could be months.
我正是这个意思
Look, that's what I'm saying.
得到26张选票并不容易
The road to 26 votes is not an easy one.
好吧  时局确实奇怪  米卡
All right. Strange days indeed, Mika.
这些是短篇小说的开头吗
So are these the start to short stories?
现在还不是什么  只是片段
They're nothing yet. Fragments.
碎片
Pieces.
显然这是关于我的
I mean, clearly, this is about me.
这是我母亲
This is my mother.
这是我们
And this is us.
-你不能写  -我要写
- You can't write-- - I'm writing.
这是我的工作  我是个作家
It's what I do. I'm a writer.
我知道你很不满  汤姆  但是
I know you're frustrated, Tom, but--
不是不满
I wouldn't say frustrated.
这是侵犯
Well, it's invasive.
-写你自己的经历  -这是我的经历
- Write about your own experiences. - This is my experience.
听着  汤姆
Listen, Tom,
我们决定弗兰西斯和我要留在这里
just because we've decided Francis and I need to stay here,
不代表你也是
doesn't mean you have to.
如果你有事
So if you have things you need to do,
就应该去做
you should go ahead and do them.
我这一天得说服参议院给我投票
I'll be spending my day convincing the Senate to vote for me,
不需要演讲
so there's no speeches necessary.
好
Yeah, okay.
你知道吗  我确实有事情要做
You know what? I do have some things to do.
我需要去找一些人  所以
Some people I need to check in with. So...
汤姆
Tom.
怎么了
Yeah?
什么事
Yes?
准备好了吗  安德伍德夫人
You ready, Mrs. Underwood?
我会安排一辆车等你
I'll have a car waiting for you.
你想先听好消息还是坏消息
So do you want the good news or the bad news first?
永远先听坏消息
Always the bad.
总统的支持率已跌至19%
The president's approvals are down to 19%.
好消息
And the good?
国会情况更糟
They're worse for Congress.
而你是30%
And you're at 30.
幸好我们现在要说服的是国会
Well, thankfully it's congress we have to convince now,
不是民众
not the public.
这些是选举前我们要解决的剩下的参议员
These are the remaining senators we'll target before the vote.
对了  都是女人
All women, by the way.
最大的挑战将是
The biggest challenges will be
印第安纳州的新晋参议员苏珊·纽曼
Indiana's freshman senator Susan Newman.
宪法律师
The constitutional lawyer?
以及夏威夷的凯芮·奎立马
And Hawaii's Kerry Kuilima,
她似乎很高兴
who seems to be enjoying
终于能有一次实权了
getting to wield a little power for once.
我必须告诉你  国会对同时为
I need to tell you, there is a lot of pushback on the Hill
总统和副总统投票抵触情绪很高
about the simultaneous vote for president and VP.
国民很担心这会导致总统副总统不同党
The country is terrified it'll lead to a split ticket.
有人可能阻挠议事
There's threats of a filibuster.
参议院现在是民主党的
Well, the Dems won the Senate,
他们想跟众议院一起投票的
and they want to vote when the House does.
这已经决定了
That decision's been made.
副总统也不会允许议员以任何形式
And the vice president won't allow a filibuster of any kind
阻挠议事
onto the floor.
夫人  你有没有考虑过这样的结果
Ma'am, have you contemplated how it could possibly work,
你做康威总统的副总统
you as vice president to President Conway?
不会那样的
That's not going to happen.
当然
Of course.
我倒是真知道奥古斯都·安德伍德的一件事
I did learn one true thing about Augustus Underwood.
什么事
What?
他死了  真死了
He was dead. Cold.
他的尸体被放在一辆马车上...
They put him on a cart...
上面有好多有待埋葬的尸体
bunch of dead bodies to bury.
一天一夜之后...
Then, after a full day and night...
他醒了
he woke up.
什么
What?
有人偷走了他的鞋和军服上的扣子  但是
Someone stole his shoes and the buttons off his uniform, but...
他活过来了
he lived.
几天后  他赶上了他所在的军团
Few days later, he caught up to his regiment.
真的吗
Really?
我得回去面对那些混乱了
I have to get back to the madness.
希望还能再见到你  总统先生
I hope I get to see you again, Mr. President.
艾瑞克...你不参加重演活动时
Eric... what do you do when you're not,
都干些什么
reenacting?
我是一名演员
I'm an actor.
有时候是吧
Sometimes.
只要有人雇  我也可以干其它的
I mean, I'd do a lot more if someone would let me.
现在  我主要做私人教练
So, right now, I'm mostly a personal trainer.
-私人教练  -是的
- A personal trainer? - Yeah.
你知道我的联系方式
You know where to find me.
还有  总统阁下...
And, sir...
不管情况看起来多糟糕...
no matter how dire things look...
你都能熬出头的
you're gonna come out of this alive.
你毕竟是安德伍德家的人
You're an Underwood, after all.
不  别耍嘴皮子  埃莉诺
No, don't... don't "Chief-of-staff" me, Eleanor.
不  不要给我他的行程
No, don't give me his schedule.
我不想知道
I don't want to hear
罗梅洛议员在会见选民
about how Congressman Romero is meeting with his constituents
或是滞留在阿西乐特快上了
or stuck on an Acela train.
你叫法齐奥  对吗
You know, it's Fazio, right?
是这么发音的吧
The pronunciation?
埃莉诺·法齐奥
Eleanor Fazio?
我只是想确认一下
I... I just want to be sure.
因为等总统获胜  他一定会获胜的
Because when the president wins, and he is going to win,
我会记得你的
I will remember your name.
我还是需要你过目一下这篇发布稿
I still need you to review this release.
很明显  目标是
Now, obviously, the goal is
抵住"躲藏"的论调
to combat the "hiding out" narrative,
强调他们正在做的工作
emphasizing the work that they're doing.
-私事吗  -公事
- Is it a personal matter? - Business.
我只有公事
It's always business.
我会签好字电邮给你的
I'll e-mail you my sign off.
等等
Wait a second.
我需要他们明天的最新行程
I need an update on their schedule for tomorrow.
-胜利就在眼前  -告诉我你是怎么知道的
- We're almost there. - I want to know how you found out.
如果他需要帮助
If he needs help,
等他入主白宫后随时可以找我
that can happen after he makes it to the White House.
马克  你还没有回答我的问题
Mark, you're not answering my question.
如果他接受治疗的消息
If word of treatment,
任何形式的治疗  泄露了...
any kind of treatment, got out--
他的朋友给他看了那种治疗方法
His friend was showing him the therapy.
-仅此而已  -请不要侮辱我
- That's it. - Please don't insult me.
你以为你是谁
Who do you think you are?
插手我们生活的方方面面
Inserting yourself into every aspect of our lives.
你丈夫的选举需要帮助
Your husband's campaign needed help.
-我就伸出了援手  -是的  但是...
- Help arrived. - Yes, but--
这原来可是你的意思  对吧
Help that you, most of all, pushed for. Yes?
-谁告诉你虚拟现实疗法的  -他自己说的
- Who told you about the VR therapy? - He did.
我们走吧
Let's go.
怎么了
What's going on?
我就是在跟马克说我非常怀念马歇尔在的时候
I was just telling Mark how much I miss having Marshall around.
他还在啊
Well, he's still around.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
我忘拿包了
I forgot my bag.
就在这里
It's right here.
喂  是的
Hello. Yeah.
是的  他在
Yes, sir, he's right here.
是他
It's him.
议员先生
Congressman.
你根本不知道这可能会多糟
You have no idea how bad this could get.
我们可别迟到
We don't wanna be late.
我万分赞同
Well, I couldn't agree more.
她可能去了圣达菲
She might have gone to Santa Fe.
你不相信我  是吗
You don't believe me, do you?
我需要看到点切实的东西  丽萨
I would need to see something, Lisa. Something concrete.
我有照片  我有一张
I have a photo. I have one, but...
听我说
Listen.
看着我
Look at me.
你不是第一个来找我对安德伍德和他手下
You're not the first person to come here making false claims
提出虚假指控的人了
about Underwood and his cronies.
但我说的是实话
But I'm telling the truth.
但你说的一切都可能是报纸上读来的
Everything you're saying you could've read in the paper.
我就是这样知道他的身份的  因为报纸登了
That's how I realized who he was. His picture in the paper.
这样你的说法就更难证实了  我们在兜圈子
Which makes your story harder to prove. We're talking in circles.
那我车坏掉时  道格·斯坦普开车送我回家呢
What about Doug Stamper driving me home when my car broke down,
还跟我说他叫彼得  是卖保险的
telling me his name was Peter and that he sold insurance?
-没人能证实你的说法  -瑞秋
- No one can corroborate that story. - Rachel!
瑞秋可以
Rachel could.
-你该吃完  -我不饿
- You should finish that. - I'm not hungry.
或许我饿了  我不知道
Maybe I am. I don't know.
我想感谢你来联络我
I want to thank you for reaching out.
我不是说我不相信你
I am not saying I don't believe you.
但已经有足够可以
But there's already enough evidence out there
扳倒总统的证据了
to take the president down.
这次选举  会让他背负更多罪责
And now, with this election, he'll be accountable for even more.
-我确定  -我不在乎
- I'm certain of it. - I don't care.
我不在乎安德伍德  我要你去找道格·斯坦普
I don't care about Underwood. I want you to talk to Doug Stamper.
我要你查明我的...
I want you to find out what happened to my...
算了  拉倒吧
Whatever, forget it.
-等等  -谢谢你的三明治
- Uh. Hold on. - Thanks for the sandwich.
好吧  等等
All right. Hold on.
有一个关于林登·约翰逊的故事我很喜欢
There's a story that I love about LBJ.
那是64或65年的时候
Uh, it was back in '64 or '65.
有个议员在躲他  那议员回到自己的办公室
A congressman was ducking him... and he came back to his office
总统就坐在他的椅子上
to find the president sitting in his chair...
等着他
waiting for him.
总统一小时内要见到你
The president expects to see you within the hour.
法齐奥小姐会告诉你具体情况
Miss Fazio can give you the specifics.
-他戴着牛仔帽  -什么
- He was wearing his cowboy hat. - What?
约翰逊总统  你漏掉了故事最精彩的部分
President Johnson. You left out the best part of the story.
我们昨晚玩到那里闭店  多谢邀请
We closed the place down last night. Thanks for the invite.
我们几个人今晚还去那里
Bunch of us are headed back to the same spot tonight,
要一起来吗
if you wanna come.
好啊  他今天午饭吃的晚  4点才会回来
Cool. Uh, he has a late lunch today. Won't be back till 4:00.
-我就是来送这个  -好
- Oh, I just needed to drop this for him. - Sure.
下次  问就好
Next time, just ask.
今晚见
See you tonight.
你赌了一把  但输了
You gambled and you lost.
其实  跟八周前比  我党团席位增多了
Actually, my bloc gained seats more than eight weeks ago.
我猜你就是为这事找我
Which I suspect is why I'm here.
别高估了你的位置
Don't overestimate your position.
或是低估了我的
Or underestimate mine.
你还没当选总统呢  先生
You still haven't been elected president, sir.
是啊  但如果党派背弃了你
Yeah, but the presidency won't matter
总统之职就无所谓了吧
once the party turns its back on you, will it?
等鲍勃·博奇教训好了你其他的绵羊
When Bob Birch puts all the rest of your sheep in line,
你会求着不被孤立
you'll be begging to come in from the cold.
两年后  你会回到凤凰城
And two years from now, you'll be back in Phoenix
一遍遍在脑海里回顾这一刻
replaying this very moment over and over again in your mind
意识到  这就是结束的开始
and realizing it was the beginning of the end.
帕特里夏·惠特克和民主党
Patricia Whittaker and the Democratic Party
会跟你撇清关系
will wipe their hands of you.
-我是忠于党的  -那是应该的
- I'm loyal to the party. - As you should be.
你应该这么说
As you should say.
但说真的
But really...
你有什么筹码
what's your leverage?
委员会  那已经完了
The committee? That's done.
瞧  你已经献了身  艾力克斯
You see, you've already put out, Alex,
威尔·康威却不打算带你去舞会
and Will Conway is not taking you to the prom.
我跟州长的谈话
My conversations with the governor
和我可能的立场...
and any position that I may or may not have--
听听自己的话  你相信自己吗
Oh, listen to yourself. Do you even believe you?
你作为一个
You are awfully confident
已经输了一次选举的人  好自信啊
for someone who's already lost the election once.
帮个忙  暂时忘记总统的事
Do me a favor. Forget the presidency for just a moment.
你没有...资本
You don't have... the capital
来推动你掀起的国会革命
to build on the congressional revolution that you've started,
不管是政治上还是其他的
politically or otherwise.
我们的运动想让事态爆发
Our movement wants to explode things--
得了  少拿那套革新派公关套路我
Oh, please. Spare me your progressive PR bullshit.
你和他们想要的东西一样
You want what they all want.
权力  更好的地位
Access. A better seat at the table.
你的名字在他人之前
Your name before the rest.
这我可以给你
And that is something that I can give you.
你想换取多少选票呢
And how many votes do you want in exchange?
你不断增长的党团给我三张就行
Just three from your ever-growing bloc
我就能在关键代表团获得胜利
would assure me the win in key delegations.
具体点
Specifically?
缅因州  威斯康星州和新罕布什尔还未定
Maine, Wisconsin and New Hampshire are still in play.
三个全要
All three?
我相信你  议员  想知道为什么吗
I believe in you, Congressman. Do you wanna know why?
说吧
Tell me.
因为我相信野心
Because I trust ambition.
-那这是直截了当的贿赂喽  -不  议员
- So this is a straight-up bribe. - Oh, no, Congressman.
贿赂是你可以拒绝的
A bribe is something you can refuse.
鉴于你的经验没有我丰富
Now, since you haven't been around the block as many times as I have,
我来教教你这事怎么办吧
let me walk you through how this works.
抱歉  总统  但我知道是怎么回事
Excuse me, Mr. President, but I do know how this is done.
那太好了
Oh, well, that's good to hear.
我从缅因州开始吧  她欠我的
I'll start with Maine. She owes me.
我们以前见过一次的  总统先生
You know, we did meet once before, Mr. President.
2012年大会的一次晚宴上
At a dinner, during the 2012 convention.
-我还想向你自我介绍来着  -然后呢
- I tried to introduce myself to you... - And?
-你不记得我了  是吗  -为什么要记得呢
- You don't remember, do you? - Why would I?
主持人为什么那么在意布洛哈特的意见
Why is the moderator so interested in Brockhart's opinion?
所有人都突然忘记我才是总统候选人了吗
Has everyone suddenly forgotten now I'm at the top of the ticket?
当然没有
No, of course not.
结束了吗
Are we done here?
是啊  我们谈谈明天的日程吧
Yeah. We should talk about tomorrow's schedule.
目前票数不错
Uh, vote's looking good now.
我们还得尽量多找些议员谈
We still need to talk to as many congressmen as we can.
你去安排  然后打给我们
Well, you figure it out and give us a call.
别再安排针对军事委员会的活动了
And, uh, enough with the events targeting the Armed Services.
我们在这边拉票已经到极限了
We got as many Congress people as we could get out of this.
别介意  将军  但我们该分头行动  好吗
No offense, General, but we need to divide and conquer. Okay?
威尔  我之前跟马克谈了
Will, I was speaking with Mark...
-怎么  -我想告诉你
- Yeah. - ...and I want you to know,
如果你需要谈什么  我随时奉陪
if you need to talk about anything, I'm available.
我唯一需要的支持  将军
The only support I need, General...
就是一个副总统对总统的支持  好吗
is that of a vice president to his president. Okay?
塔伯特参议员的首要考虑是经济适用房
Senator Talbert's priorities are affordable housing
和堵住企业税务漏洞
and closing corporate tax loopholes.
尤其是高等教育普及
And access to higher education especially.
通话在10点
The call is in ten.
艾丹·麦卡伦为什么跑了
Why did Aidan Macallan run away?
什么
What?
麦卡伦为什么跑了
Why did Macallan run away?
我也不知道
I wish I could tell you.
时间不多了
Clock's ticking.
请给我汤姆·耶茨司机的号码
Yes, give me Tom Yates' driver's number, please.
喂
Yes.
是  夫人
Yes, ma'am.
纽约
New York.
你一路开去了纽约
You drove all the way to New York?
在哪
Where?
他跟谁在一起
Who's he with?
我不知道  一个女人  年纪较长
I don't know. A woman. Older.
我不知道那要怎么做  夫人
I don't know how that'll work, ma'am.
是  我试试
Yes. Yes, I'll try.
不  我理解你的担忧  参议员
No, I understand your concern, Senator.
学生贷款改革是你的优先考虑
Student loan reform is a priority for you,
那么它就也是总统和我的优先考虑
so it will be a priority for the president and me.
是的  没错
Yes. Yes, I do.
露易丝  你是党派中流砥柱
Well, Louise, you as a pillar of the party,
如果你明天能帮我  我会感激不尽
it will be much appreciated if I can get your help tomorrow.
到时就你和我  还有几个你的
And it'll just be you and me and a couple of your...
参议院女同事
female colleagues in the Senate.
好  那么我期待与你有成效地谈谈
Okay, well, I look forward to a productive dialogue.
-迟到总比不来好  -抱歉我错过了晚餐
- Better late than never. - Sorry I missed dinner.
为什么坐后面
Why the back?
我在假装你是优步  帮帮忙
I'm pretending you're an Uber. Just help me out.
我的小姑子  你没来她就来了
My sister-in-law. She came when you couldn't.
你觉得死者会鄙视我们吗
Do you think the dead judge us?
不会
No.
你最喜欢他做什么
What did he do that you liked the most?
在床上
Here... in bed.
坐姿最好
Sitting up was the best.
腿缠着彼此
Legs around each other.
他会把右手
He'd run his right hand
伸到我脖子后面  插进我的头发里拽着
up the back of my neck into my hair and pull it.
把我的头发和脑袋往后拽
My hair and my head back...
然后呢
And?
然后用另一只手  把我拉进拉出
And with the other hand, he'd pull me in and out.
他始终看着我
Always looking at me.
看到我
Seeing me.
你要我那么做吗
You want me to do that?
嗯
Yeah.
这里真好  几乎听不到他们的吼声
It's so nice in here. You can hardly hear them.
相信我  我听得到的
Oh, trust me, I can hear them.
加上新罕布什尔  多少了
With New Hampshire, it's what?
24  加缅因州25
Twenty-four. With Maine, 25.
-如果拿下威斯康星就是26  -汤姆呢
- Twenty-six if we get Wisconsin. - Where's Tom?
他去喘口气了
He needed to get some air.
-威斯康星很顽固  -那还有谁
- Wisconsin is being stubborn. - Then who else?
爱荷华  或许科罗拉多  那是24  25
Iowa, maybe Colorado, 24, 25.
你的曾曾曾祖父奥古斯都怎么样了
How was your great-great-great-grandfather Augustus?
他叫艾瑞克
He goes by Eric.
艾瑞克
Eric.
他很欣赏我的手艺
He admired my craftsmanship.
-我们该争取一下北达科他  -同意
- We should make a play for North Dakota. - Agreed.
在参议院  你应该可以拉密苏里的票
In the Senate, I think you can swing some votes from Missouri.
你问莉安麦卡伦的事了吗
Did you ask LeAnn about Macallan?
她并不知情  我相信她
She didn't know anything. I believe her.
我们又得戒了
We have to quit again.
否则  会害死我们的
Otherwise, they'll kill us.
麦卡伦不见踪影  但他去过那儿  留下了财物
No Macallan. He was there, though. Left his belongings.
国家警察那里有消息吗
Anything from the National Police?
没有  中情局的内部人士
No. CIA's man in the palace
甚至不确定他是否还在雅加达
isn't even sure he's still in Jakarta.
他们会找到他的  莉安  我只能说这么多
They'll find him, LeAnn. That's all I can give you.
多谢帮忙
I appreciate your help.
凯芮  苏珊  需要点什么
Kerry, Susan, what can I get you?
-不用  谢谢  -水就行
- I'm fine, thanks. - I'm good with water.
-你呢  露易丝  -你喝什么
- What about you, Louise? - What are you having?
-伏特加加冰  -给我也来一杯
- Splash of vodka on ice. - Make it two.
苏珊和我来的路上谈了  克莱尔
Susan and I were talking on the way over, Claire.
这场选举的混乱让我们
This election mess has left us
都面临着一些可怕的可能性
all facing some scary possibilities.
-康威拿下众议院  -这还远非定数
- Conway wins in the House-- - Which is far from inevitable.
但如果真发生总统副总统不同党
But if a split ticket were to happen...
那对国家会不利的
it would be bad for this country.
不  康威才对国家不利
No, Conway is what would be bad for this country.
希望众议院能做出正确选择
Let's hope the House does the right thing.
但就参议院而言
But as far as the Senate,
我很高兴有唐纳德·布莱斯掌舵
I am very grateful that we have Donald Blythe steering that ship.
安德伍德夫人  我很抱歉这么说
Mrs. Underwood, I'm sorry to say this,
但不管你能拿出什么
but no matter what you're offering here,
我都不能支持总统
I can't support the president.
也因此不能支持你
And, by extension, I can't support you.
不是你的问题  克莱尔  是他
It's not you, Claire. It's him.
苏珊和我在这事上的意见是一致的
Susan and I are on the same page about this.
如果重点不是弗兰西斯·安德伍德呢
What if this isn't about Francis Underwood, huh?
前途大好的是克莱尔·安德伍德
It's Claire Underwood who has the promising future.
我希望一个女人入主白宫
I want a woman in the White House.
如果她得从副总统做起  那好
And if she has to start as a vice president, fine.
但时候到了
But it's time.
-时候到了  -我赞同  露易丝
- It's time. - I hear that, Louise,
但我直说吧
but I'll say it...
投票给你  就是投给弗兰克·安德伍德
A vote for you is a vote for Frank Underwood.
我理解你们对弗兰西斯历史的担忧  真的
Listen, I understand your concerns about Francis' record. I do.
如果康威赢了
If Conway wins,
难道你们不希望有个民主党人克制着他吗
wouldn't you want a Democrat to keep him in check?
如果给我投票不等于给弗兰西斯投票呢
And what if a vote for me isn't necessarily a vote for Francis?
21票确定是你  先生
Twenty-one promised for you, sir.
康威是23
Twenty-three for Conway.
两个僵持  四个未知
Two deadlocked. Four unknown.
但我觉得党团会议之后情况会变动
But I think things will shift once they caucus.
-好  叫他进来  -是  先生
- All right, let's bring him in. - Yes, sir.
-请坐  -我不久留
- Have a seat. - I won't be long.
那就站着吧
Well, then, stand like a man
像个不知是否该坐下的人
who doesn't know whether to sit or not.
罗梅洛议员  你为我带来好消息了吗
Congressman Romero, do you have good news for me?
你的革新人士想明白了吗
Have your progressives seen the light?
我已经尽力了  总统先生  我无法说服他们
I did what I could, Mr. President. I couldn't sway the bloc.
无法  还是不愿
Couldn't... or wouldn't?
缅因和新罕布什尔还不明朗
Maine and New Hampshire are noncommittal.
沃考特议员在让威斯康星支持康威
Congressman Wolcott is turning Wisconsin for Conway.
告诉我点别的事实
Tell me a different truth.
他们不听我的
They aren't listening to me.
他们相信  与让康威当选相比
They believe supporting you would do more damage
支持你会给民主党和国家造成更大损害
to the Democratic Party and the country than a Conway presidency.
很遗憾  竟然走到这一步
Well, I am sorry that it has come to this.
我也是  我们肯定还会再见的  先生
As am I. I'm sure we'll meet again, sir.
是啊  但你走之前  好好看看这间屋子
Yes, but before you go, just take a look around this room.
仔细看每处细节  每个方面
Study every detail, every aspect.
因为这是你最后一次踏进这里了
Because this is the last time you will ever step foot in here.
抱歉我没帮上更多忙
I'm sorry I couldn't be of more help.
想想吧  你本能让自己因为很多其他事
And to think you could have made yourself memorable
被世人铭记的
in so many other ways.
我会确保他再进不了其他委员会  先生
I'll make sure he never sees another committee, sir.
不  他希望我们还击  让他感觉更强大
Oh, no. He wants us to put up a fight, make him feel bigger.
他只不过是看了民调数据  就以为我有麻烦
He's just read some polls and thinks I'm in trouble.
所以他才攻击我
That's why he's coming after me.
好吧  我们有48小时
All right, we have 48 hours.
我得攻下科罗拉多  稳住田纳西
I have to work Colorado and shore up Tennessee.
但哪怕不惜一切  也要让
But Maine, Wisconsin and New hampshire
缅因  威斯康星和新罕布什尔回心转意
must be turned by any means necessary.
所有党团会议周四中午之前都会结束
All caucusing will end by noon on Thursday,
下午两点
and then the vote in both
参众两院开始投票
the House and the Senate is scheduled for 2:00.
我不做决定  查克  我只是传达而已
Well... I don't make the decisions, Chuck. I just relay them.
不  不  目前不做声明
No. No, there will not be a statement at this time.
因为投票结果出来前无话可说
Well, because there's nothing to state until after the vote.
关上门
Close the door.
嗯  对
Right. Yes.
对
Yes.
求你别再逼我说"对"了
Yeah, please don't make me say yes again.
美国现在真是疯了
Crazy days in these United States.
你想告诉我  是什么重要到
So you wanna tell me what was so important
我得放你进来
I had to get you through the gates?
有个叫丽萨·威廉姆斯的女孩来过
Girl named Lisa Williams came in.
说她曾是瑞秋·波斯纳的女朋友
Says she was Rachel Posner's girlfriend.
她说道格·斯坦普认识瑞秋
Said Doug Stamper knew Rachel.
觉得他可能和瑞秋失踪有关
Feels like maybe he was involved in her disappearance.
她说道格·斯坦普这个名字了吗
And she said the words "Doug Stamper"?
瑞秋·波斯纳失踪的时间
Rachel Posner went missing around the time
正好是斯坦普被劫车  脑袋被砸的时候
Stamper was carjacked and had his head bashed in.
这个丽萨觉得
And this Lisa thinks...
她也不太确定
Well, she's not sure exactly.
她能证明其中有联系吗
Well, can she prove a connection?
现在都只是直觉
It's all instinct at this point.
拜托
Come on.
你要是想参观白宫
You want a tour of the White House,
可以直接跟我说嘛
you could just straight up ask me for one.
-汉默施密特  -他看重这事吗
- Hammerschmidt. - Is he making anything of it?
还不  但关于她的资料已经在他桌上了
Not yet. But the information about her is on the top of his desk.
丽萨·威廉姆斯
Lisa Williams.
格雷森先生  三号线有人找
Mr. Grayson, you have a call on line three.
我得工作了
Well, I gotta get back to it.
要是汤姆继续跟进她  就告诉我
If Tom follows up on her, let me know.
-谢谢你给的通行证  -是临时的
- Thanks for the pass. - It's temporary.
好吧
Okay.
-莉安·哈维  -你总熬夜
- LeAnn Harvey. - Always burning the midnight oil.
-艾丹  -你准备好来找我了吗
- Aidan? - You ready to join me?
你知道你把我推进了多危险的境地吗
Do you have any idea how much jeopardy you have put me in?
你应该趁还有机会逃出来
You should've gotten out when you had the chance.
你觉得你就逃出来了
You think you're out?
-听着  我需要你帮我个忙  -你在哪
- Listen, I need you to do me a favor. - Where are you?
让联调局  中情局
Get the FBI, CIA,
和其他在找我的人都停下  马上
and whoever else is looking for me to stop, now.
好  艾丹  你就
Okay, Aidan, you know, just...
先回来  我们一起想办法
come back here, and we will figure this out together.
要是他们继续找我
If they keep coming after me,
我就开始泄露关于安德伍德夫妇的秘密
I will start leaking things about the Underwoods.
你不想那么做的
You don't wanna do that.
你不知道你现在是在为什么人工作  莉安
You have no idea who you're working for, LeAnn.
该死
God damn it.
有新情况向总统汇报吗
You have an update for the president?
我今天基本上一直在忙着应付参议员
I've been juggling senators most of the day.
你那缅因州的议员呢
And your congressman from Maine?
依然是我朋友的父亲  依然没时间见面
Is still my friend's father and is still too busy to meet.
威斯康星和新罕布什尔也一样
So was Wisconsin and New Hampshire,
我逼他们就见到了
until I forced them to.
你有你的风格  我有我的
You have your style, I have mine.
总统不在乎风格  莉安
The president doesn't care about style, LeAnn.
周四前把议员的票拉到位就行
Just get the congressman by the vote on Thursday.
威尔刚进来了
Will just walked in.
嗯
Yeah.
行
Okay.
再联系  拜
Talk soon. Bye.
-你妈妈  -对  她向你问好
- That your mom? - Yeah. She sends her best.
好吧
Yeah.
-查理人呢  -在客厅
- Where's Charlie? - In the living room.
莉莉在小房间玩
Lily's playing in the den.
-你要去哪  -我该换衣服了
- Where are you going? - I should change.
-你一直躲着我  汉娜  -拜托
- You keep walking away from me, Hannah. - Oh, please.
你为什么邀请他来
Why would you invite him here?
这个时候
Now?
他是朋友  你的朋友
He's a friend. He's your friend.
我想也许...
And I thought maybe...
你会有兴趣看一看
it'd be something that you'd be interested in looking at.
我在尽力而为
I'm doing all I can.
-尽力而为  -是的
- All you can? - Yes.
质疑我
Like doubt me?
以为你比我更了解我自己的精神状况
Like think that you know better what's in my mind than I do?
要知道  是你告诉马克的
You know, you're the one who told Mark.
我还得否认我跟那事有关
I had to deny I had anything to do with it.
要知道这些人  汉娜  厄舍和马歇尔
See, these people, Hannah... Usher and Marshall...
他们是雇工  不能信他们
they're hired hands. They can't be trusted.
布洛哈特也是为了自己
And Brockhart, he's in it for himself.
但你...亲爱的  我的爱人
But... but you, my darling, my love--
-别说了  -别说什么
- Stop it. - Stop what?
你能怎么样  带孩子回娘家
What are you gonna do? Take the kids and go to your mom?
你不会这么做的
As if you would.
你连白宫的瓷器都挑好了
You already picked out the White House china.
你最大的心愿就是当上总统
You want this more than anything. To be president.
这也成了我的心愿  你胆敢来指责我
Don't you dare judge me now that I want it, too.
是  议员  安排航程也算贿赂
Yes, Congressman, but flights are considered bribes.
是  议员  我们担心的不是你的酒驾
Yes, Congressman, it's not your DUIs that concern us,
而是你女儿的
it's your daughter's.
那你本该把开销藏得更深
Well, you should've done a better job hiding the payouts.
拜托
I mean, really.
嗯  我相信你是  他多大来着
Yes, I'm sure you are... but how old was he again?
对  他参加过合唱团  对吧
Yes, and he was in the choir, is that right?
但你没法把邮件删得不留痕迹
But you can never erase an e-mail,
我过世的姑姑都知道
even my dead aunt knows that.
好吧  你尽快回复我
Well, get back to me as soon as you can.
-怎么样  -缅因州终于搞定了  先生
- So? - Maine finally looks solid, sir.
但新罕布什尔还没有
New Hampshire doesn't, though.
我坐在这里好几个小时
I've been sitting in here for hours
想方设法取得了一些成效
busting my ass, getting some results.
我们本应拿下新罕布什尔的
We should have secured New Hampshire.
莉安怎么拿下缅因州的
How did LeAnn get Maine?
对方欠她人情
She cashed in a favor.
那你为什么不能用同一招
Well, why couldn't you do the same goddamn thing?
我想不通
It doesn't make sense.
我以为我说服他了
I thought I had him. I mean...
不只是新罕布什尔  威斯康星本来也该拿下的
And it's not just New Hampshire. Wisconsin should've folded.
本来
Should have?
怎么回事  道格  你怎么了
What's going on, Doug? What's happening?
是你的投入  还是忠心出了问题
Is there some issue with your commitment? Your loyalty?
什么
What?
或许你就不值得我信任
Perhaps you just aren't worthy of my trust.
我为你费尽心力
I have given everything to you.
我的整个职业生涯几乎都给了你  弗兰克
Almost the entirety of my professional life, Frank.
你注意语气
You watch your tone.
我做的那些事...
The things I've done...
为了保住你的位子  我做的那些事...
The things that I have done to help keep you here,
你居然还质疑我的忠心
and you're gonna question my loyalty?
如果我们不能赢
Well, if we can't win,
那我们得确保康威也不能赢
we have to make sure that Conway doesn't either.
缅因州支持我们  那他就拿不到26票
Maine coming over only means he won't get to 26.
僵局不是胜局  但至少...
A deadlock isn't a win. But at least...
抱歉  道格  我刚才失态了
I'm sorry, Doug. I was out of line.
我们继续工作吧
Let's get back to work.
不只是他如何处理了那些数据
It's not just what he did with all the data.
艾丹之前能接触到一切
Aidan had access to everything.
我们得让中情局和联调局不去查他
We need to get the CIA and FBI off his trail,
我需要你的帮助
and I need your help.
你在制造麻烦  莉安
You're causing problems, LeAnn,
我们现在最要不得麻烦了
which is the last thing that we can afford right now.
麦卡伦是作茧自缚
Macallan sealed his own fate.
我拿下了缅因州  道格
I delivered Maine, Doug,
你可没处理好新罕布什尔
which is more than you can say about New Hampshire.
算我欠你人情
I'll owe you.
还不够
Not enough.
总统跟你说过艾丹的事吗
Has the president spoken to you about Aidan at all?
没有
No.
他在狙杀名单上吗
Is he on a kill list?
美利坚合众国没有狙杀名单  莉安
The United States of America doesn't have kill lists, LeAnn.
我是唯一阻止麦卡公布他手上的东西的人
I am the only thing preventing Mac from releasing what he has.
我猜不管那是什么  你也牵涉其中
And my guess is, whatever it is, it'll implicate you, too.
我错了吗  道格
Am I wrong, Doug?
米切尔参议员身边的人告诉了我这消息
Someone close to Senator Mitchell woke me up with the news.
让副总统接电话
Get me the vice president on the phone.
没用
That is not going to help.
你打算怎么处理
Well, how do you intend on dealing with it?
唐纳德
Donald.
-别这么做  -克莱尔
- Don't do it. - Claire--
我知道你和米切尔参议员在谋划什么
I know what you and Senator Mitchell were planning.
做你本该做的事
Do what you were supposed to do.
取消阻挠议事  好让参议院能投票
Move the anti-filibuster measure forward so the Senate can vote
-选我担任副总统  -不行
- and elect me vice president. - No.
-不行  -各方声音都应该被听到
- No? - All voices should be heard
出于对美国人民的尊重
out of respect for the American people
也因为今天参议院投票的重要性
and the gravity of the vote before the Senate today,
自1825年起  这还是首次
the first like this since 1825.
众议院即将投票  唐纳德  怎么回事
The House is about to vote, Donald. What is going on?
我们把这事弄完  你就能回家了
Let's get this done so you can go home.
看上去康威要赢了
It looks like Conway is going to win.
不管别人跟你说了什么
And no matter what people have told you,
参议院会投给布洛哈特
the Senate is voting for Brockhart.
-国家高于政党  克莱尔  -你在耍滑头吗
- It's country over party, Claire. - Are you flexing?
我想拖到众议院完成投票
I'm stalling until the House vote happens
好让参议院据结果投票
and then the Senate votes accordingly.
你要那样对待
You'd do that to the party
你将全部事业倾注其中的政党吗
to which you've devoted your entire career?
国家需要透明和决议
The country needs clarity and resolution.
那是最重要的事
That's the most important thing.
四年后还会有选举
There'll be another election in four years.
但听我说
But look...
弗兰西斯昏迷时  我看到了你的样子
I saw you when Francis was in the coma.
当得到机会时你展现出的能力
What you're capable of when given the opportunity.
你今后还有机会  我会为你投票
You still have a shot down the road. I'd vote for you.
不管你怎么想  我知道我票数够了
Whatever you think, I know I have the numbers.
我不这么认为
I don't think so.
但拜托
But come on.
你不像他  耐心点
You're not like him. Be patient.
你是个傻瓜  唐纳德  一直都是
You're a fool, Donald. You always were.
你和你三句不离的那个蠢亡妻
You and your dumb, dead wife that you never, ever shut up about.
有原则  理想主义
Principled? Idealistic?
捍卫人民  你实际做过什么
A champion for the people? What did you ever actually do?
什么也没有
Nothing.
伟大的斗士  我看不是
The great crusader? I don't think so.
你只是喜欢你现在这副傻瓜的样子
You just liked the position of the bumbling idiot that you are.
乐观主义者  理想主义者
The optimist. The idealist.
你太喜欢了以至于你甚至不能达成一笔协议
You loved it so much that you couldn't even make a deal
或者推进一件事
or move a single thing forward.
你什么也没有留下
You have a legacy of nothing.
取消阻挠议事  让共和党别碍事
Sign the measure, get the Republicans off the floor,
马上开始投票
start the vote now.
你知道我刚刚意识到什么吗
Do you know what I just realized?
你的姓名首字母
Your initials...
少了N和T[贱人]
they're missing an "N" and a "T".
投票无结果  总统先生
The vote is inconclusive, Mr. President.
你和康威都没达到26票
Neither you nor Conway to 26.
还有机会  克莱尔怎么样
Still alive. What about Claire?
这不可能
This is impossible.
我和你一样惊讶
I'm as surprised as you are.
缅因州  毫无征兆
Maine. There was no heads-up on that.
我知道这令人沮丧  这本该结束了
Look, I know this is frustrating. It should be over.
我是总统
I... I'm the president.
我不管他们说什么  我
I don't care what they say, I...
我就是该死的美国总统
I'm fucking President of the United States.
不  你不是
No, you're not.
直到众议院做出决定
The vice president will be acting president
副总统将代总统职
for as long as it takes the House to decide.
我该去打几个电话
I should make some calls.
美国总统选举的过程是  选举日注册选民投票
(有的州在选举日前也可以投票  但有的州只能在当日投票)
投票结束后开始计票  媒体根据计票结果  用自己的模型得出各州结果
拿到271张选举人票为胜  如果是平局  则由众议院投票决定总统
但媒体公布结果后  具体的计票还要继续  直到统计出所有的选票
如果哪个州结果过于相近  按部分州的法律  会自动启动重新计票
计票结束后  选举委员会确定胜者  一般由州长来签名认证
需注意的是  根据法律  投票日选的其实不是总统
而是"选举人"  也就各州的"投票代表"
而选举委员会和州长认证的  也是各州的选举人名单
选举人需在大选后去华盛顿参加选举人会议
跟其他州的代表一起  再投一次票  那一次才算真正选出总统
当然大选夜之后的选举人再度投票  只是象征性的
不过美国只有29个州有法律规定  选举人在华盛顿开选举人会时
必须根据本州的选举结果投票  所以会出现个别不忠诚的选举人
在最后投票时  选择跟本州选民选举结果不同的候选人
另外在1876年大选出现选派选举人时产生争议的情况后
1877年国会立法  规定如果各州的选举人人选有争议
则由国会来决定该州的选举人  另外这个法律还规定
各州必须在选举人会议前6天向国会提交选举认证结果
在选举夜  媒体根据自己的模型判断胜负
但在法律上  必须所有的票都统计结束
由负责选举的官员进行公证后  结果才正式生效